PHIL: I've been here for five years
and every year I've worked with many
young people who are really funny.
And this specific one, I used to...
when I was, I used to work one-to-one
with a young man and he was using...
we were using, ABLLS as an
assessment, as an assessment system.
One of the main things that we were
working on, one of the reasons we
were using ABLLS is life skills, we
wanted this beautiful to start to be
able to say quarter past or half past.
And so we did a lot of work on that
and it started by, so we use a dry
wipe clock and write on different
times and, you know, say "Oh, 10:15.
That's quarter-past.
Right."
And then maybe write quarter-past
ten as well in words, and then
expand on that by giving choices.
Once you've got quarter-past
and half-past separately.
So, "Oh, it's 10:30, is that
quarter-past 10 or half-past 10?"
And that takes a bit of work.
So just give them, you know,
minimal choices, not overwhelm them.
Not placing too much demand,
not too many choices.
And when this particular pupil told me
that it was quarter-past, that 15 on a
digital clock meant quarter-past, and also
that when the big hand is on 3, that means
a quarter-past,  such was my joy I lept.
I went "yes!"
really loud.
...that huge achievement, not just
because it ticked the box for me as
a teacher, but that this person had
got that understanding and now could,
you know, was beginning to tell the
time that was such, you know, I was
so overcome with joy that it actually
scared - it made the young person jump.
So then we had to do a
bit more work after that.
We actually took a little step
back because I'd made them
jump because I was so happy.
So that was the one that
always sticks with me.